翻译: xiaochenjia   校对: 我要挂科了
后期: xiaochenjia@VeryCD
再次广播  请乘坐1457航班
Once again, for passengers
traveling on Flight 1457...
前往奥兰多的旅客  留意行李寄存检查公告
to Orlando, please take advantage of
the boarding bag-check announcement.
疾病爆发第2天
您可以在抵达奥兰多后在行李认领处领取
You'll pick it up at baggage claim in Orlando.
今天的旅程安排很紧
It's a really full flight today.
- 嘿  - 嘿  我是乔恩・尼尔
- Hey. - Yeah, Jon Neal here.
跟我在旅馆上床之后   你就这样不辞而别了
You just had sex with me in a hotel
and left without saying goodbye.
是的  当时事情比预想的推迟了些  抱歉  我当时很惊慌
Yeah, it ended up being delayed, so... Sorry, I was panicking.
好吧  如果我没有机会再见到你…
Well, if I don't get to see you again...
我只是想说很高兴再遇见你
I just wanted to say it was nice to see you again.
遇见你我也很高兴
Yeah, it was nice to see you too.
嗯  听着  用另外一个我给你的邮箱
Um, and listen, use that other e-mail I gave you...
因为只有那个邮箱比较安全  好吗?
...because that's the only secure one, okay?
好的
Okay.
你还好吗
You all right?
没事  只是…
Yeah, I'm just...
只是有点时差  我很累
I'm just jet-lagged. I'm tired.
你应该回家好好休息下  到香港的旅途可远着呢
You should go home and get some rest. Hong Kong's a long way.
乘坐5228航班
Attention passengers on Flight 5228...
- 噢  等一下  ...到明尼阿波利斯的乘客请注意
- Oh, wait. ...to Minneapolis.
是你的航班吗?
Is that you?
是的  我的航班马上要起飞了
Yep, that's me. They're calling my flight.
好吧  听着  真的很高兴你打电话给我
All right. Well, look, I'm really glad you called.
-  谢谢 再见  - 再见
- Thanks. Bye. - Bye.
请各位乘客准备好您的登机牌
Please have your boarding passes out and ready.
谢谢
Thanks.
香港九龙  人口: 二百一十万
英国伦敦  人口: 八百六十万
明尼苏达州 明尼阿波利斯  人口: 三百三十万
日本东京  人口: 三千六百万
疾病爆发第3天
亚特兰大 乔治亚  疾病控制和预防中心
- 早上好  罗杰  - 早上好
- Good morning, Roger.  - Hey.
听说你赌球输得很惨  是吗?
So you really kicked ass in that football pool, huh?
不能再选雄狮队了
得多动动脑子  而不是意气用事
You need to give up on your Lions.
Pick with your head, not your heart.
谢谢你的忠告
Yeah, thank you for the tip.
- 没事  嘿  嘿  嘿  医生  - 什么事?
- Yeah. Hey, hey. Hey, doc, uh... - Yeah?
我知道你很忙  但是…我  我…
I know you're busy. Uh... I, uh...
- 你有时间吗  - 当然
- You got a second? - Sure.
- 我有个医学方面的问题  - 请说
- I got a medical question.  - Mm-hm.
呃  我孩子在学校上课方面有点问题
Uh, my kid's been, uh, having problems at school.
- 呃  他有点注意力缺陷  - 多动症?
- Uh, attention deficit thing. - ADHD?
- 是的  - 被确诊了没?
- Yeah. - He been diagnosed yet?
问题就在这儿  学校想让他去看看医生
That's the thing. They want him to see someone.
我在想您能否给他检查下
I was wondering if you could take a look at him.
- 我真的不是这方面的医生
- 噢  这样  我不知道  我只是想…
- I'm not really that kind of doctor.
- Oh. Ha, ha. I didn't know. I just thought...
也许我可以把他转交给其他医生
Maybe I can refer someone, though.
- 真的?  - 当然  这种病是可以治愈的
- Yeah? - Yeah. It's treatable.
- 太好了  - 我们会找其他医生给他做个检查
- Okay. - We'll find someone, have them take a look.
- 应该没什么问题  - 好的
- Shouldn't be a problem. - Okay.
- 就这样吧  - 好的
- All right. - Yup.
-  谢谢你  医生  -  不用谢
- Thanks, doc. - You're welcome.
加利福尼亚州旧金山  人口: 三百五十万
为什么没人帮他?  他还好吗?
Why doesn't anybody help him? Is he okay?
看看这些帖子
Read the posts.
有人觉得是表演的  一种行为艺术
Some say it was staged. An art project.
有人说当局不愿意做尸检
Some say the authorities wouldn't do an autopsy.
掩盖事实
Covered it up.
- 掩盖什么?  - 我们也不知道
- Covered what up? - We don't know.
也许是水俣病  食用了被水银污染的鱼
Maybe Minamata disease. You know, from mercury in the fish.
以前曾经爆发过  捕鱼业的人们在抑制它
There have been outbreaks in the past.
Fishing industry suppresses it.
- "工业病"  - 没错  但刚这只有一个人而已
- "Industrial disease."  - Yeah, but it's just one man.
- 我们根本不知道发生了什么
- 这只是刚好被拍下来的一个人
- We don't know what happened.
- Just one man on video.
不是每个人都能预见自己会死在摄像机前
Not everyone has the foresight to die in front of a camera.
我担心的是那些我们没看到的死者
The ones we don't see worry me.
大量的鱼从那儿被运往全世界
Fish is shipped all over the world from there.
有多少人在吃寿司的同时阅读着你的报纸?
How many people read your paper over a plate of sushi?
艾伦  我们几乎没有给自由职业者的预算了  而且自从H1…
Alan, we have almost no freelance budget anymore, and after H1...
等等  过不了几天  这个视频就会在推特和YouTube上传遍的
You wait. A few days, this will be tweeted and YouTubed all over the planet.
我们不想成为那种刊登狼来了之类消息的报纸
We don't wanna be the paper that cries wolf.
我会给霍巴特看的  他负责健康方面的事情
I'll show it to Hobart. He does our health stuff.
你会跟他说关于我的故事吗?
你会跟他说关于我的故事  对吗?
You're gonna give him my story?
You're gonna give him my story, aren't you?
不  艾伦  我是想帮助你  这只不过是死在公交车的一个普通人罢了
No, Alan, I'm trying to help you. It's just one man on a bus.
- 我录下了这个会面过程
- 我们需要更多关于这件事情的信息
- I taped this meeting.
- We need more information than that.
这个故事都可以载入史册了  我会起诉你的
This story runs in the Chronicle, I will sue your ass.
很好  随便你  再见  艾伦  别再打电话给我了
Great. Okay, bye, Alan. Don't call me anymore.
平面媒体行业奄奄一息了  洛伦
Print media is dying, Lorraine.
快衰退了  我会给你在公交车上留个位置的
It's dying. I'll save you a seat on the bus.
你好  我是米奇・艾默霍夫  我是克拉克的继父  克拉克・莫罗
I'm Mitch Emhoff. I'm Clark's stepdad. Clark Morrow.
好的  我们会通知他你来了
All right, I'll let him know you're here.
好的
Okay.
他说他在泰特姆夫人的的班上感觉很温暖
He said he was feeling very warm  in Mrs. Tatum's class.
我在打过电话后又测了下他的体温
超过华氏100°(约为37.7°C)
I took his temperature again since I called.
It was a touch over a hundred.
好吧  先是他的妈妈病了  现在克拉克也病了?
Okay. Well, first his mom and now the mighty Clark, huh?
好了  现在回去给你和你妈妈熬点汤
All right, let's go get some soup for you and Mom.
希望能感觉好点儿 克拉克  好吗
Hope you feel better, Clark, okay?
好的  谢谢妈妈
Okay. Thank you.
乖孩子
Thattaboy.
感恩节前一定会康复的
We're gonna beat this thing down by Turkey Day.
我在得克萨斯州  我会试试的  会试试看
I'm in Texas. I'll try it. I'll try anything once.
哈哈  这不是真的
Ha, ha. That's not true.
乔瑞会直接到她妈妈那儿去
Jory's going straight from the band trip to her mom's place.
我的工作面试得推迟到下个星期了
And my job interview got pushed to next week.
我不知道这意味着什么  希望什么也不是
I'm not really sure what that means. Hopefully nothing.
怎么了
Hey.
我的手臂
My arm.
过来  坐下  坐下  坐下   小心脚下  过来
Come here, sit down, sit down, sit down.
Watch your feet. Come on.
快点  快点  亲爱的
Come on. Come on, honey.
你怎么了?  你染上流感了吗?
Okay, what happened? Did you take too much of that flu shit?
亲爱的? 贝丝  贝丝  嘿  嘿  嘿  亲爱的  亲爱的
Honey? Beth, Beth. Hey, hey, hey. Honey, honey.
贝丝  天哪  天哪  宝贝儿  宝贝儿  嘿  贝丝
Beth. Jesus. Jesus. Sweetheart. Sweetheart. Hey, Beth.
- 妈妈 -  不  不 不    就呆那儿  克拉克  别过来
- Mom?  - No, no, no. Uh... Stay there, Clark. Don't...
回你的房间去  宝贝儿  呃…
Just go... Go up to your room, honey. Uh...
亲爱的  亲爱的
Honey, honey.
- 贝丝  - 能听见我说话吗
- Beth. - Beth, can you hear me?
我是艾林顿医生  你在医院里
My name's Dr. Arrington. You're in the hospital.
今天早上你癫痫发作了  贝丝
You had a seizure this morning, Beth.
- 她有癫痫病史吗  - 没有  没有
- She have a history of seizures? - No, no, no.
- 或者对什么东西过敏?  - 呃  她好像对青霉素过敏
- Allergies? - Uh, I think she's allergic to penicillin.
- 他最近摔倒过吗?  撞到头了?  - 没有  她刚出差完回来
- She fall recently? Hit her head? - No, she came back from a trip...
嗑药没?  摇头丸?  迷幻药?
What about drugs? MDMA? Ecstasy?
没有  没有  我们没有嗑药
No. No, we don't do that.
- 好吧  这儿需要帮助  - 天哪 贝丝  贝丝
- Okay, let's get some help in here.  - Jesus. Beth. Beth.
先生  请你出去  你必须出去
Sir, you have to go. You have to go.
准备进行心脏电击抢救
Let's get a line in her.
准备2毫克安定文
And give me 2 milligrams of Ativan, please.
呃   我们尽了最大努力  但她还是没有任何反应
So, um, despite all our efforts, she failed to respond.
- 知道了  - 她心跳停止了
- Okay. - And her heart stopped...
很不幸  她去世了
and unfortunately, she did die.
明白
Right.
- 很抱歉  艾默霍先生  - 我知道这很难接受
- I'm sorry, Mr. Emhoff.  - I know this is hard to accept.
好的  我意思是  我能和她谈谈吗
Okay. I mean, so can I go talk to her?
艾默霍先生  对不起  但是你妻子已经死了
Mr. Emhoff, I'm sorry. Your wife is dead.
我刚还看着她  刚在家里还是好好的
I mean, I just saw her. We were just at home.
你还有其他可以联系到的亲人吗
Is there somebody that we can call?
你觉得应该在这儿陪伴你的人?
Someone who you think should be here with you?
我们一起吃的晚饭  一起吃披萨  她说她只是有点时差反应
I mean, we had dinner. We had pizza. She said she was jet-lagged.
你提到过她去过很远的地方  是香港吗?
You mentioned that she was away. Hong Kong?
我们看过最新的报告
We checked the latest bulletins.
那儿有麻疹和H1N1病毒病史
The only things there were measles and H1N1...
但你妻子得的不是这两种病
...and this was not that.
那是什么病?
Then what was it?
我们也不确定
We don't always know.
我是说  有些人得了病活得好好的
而有些人变得虚弱最后死去
I mean, some people get a disease
and live  some get sicker and die.
我们得通知法医…
We're gonna have to notify
the medical examiner...
…他们也许会请求做尸检
...and they may request an autopsy.
或者你希望的话  我们可以安排下
Or if you wish, we can order one.
但是我不保证这会让你得到更多有用的信息
But I can't guarantee it's gonna tell you any more than I can.
我最好的猜测是这既不是脑膜炎  也不是脑炎
I mean, my best guess is that this was either
meningitis or encephalitis...
对于脑炎  我们现在知之甚少
...and with encephalitis, we're in
the dark a lot of the time.
如果这是发生在夏天  我可能会认为是臭虫咬的
比如西尼罗河病毒
If it was summer, I might say a bug bite
you know, West Nile.
- 我不知道 - 疱疹可引起脑炎
- I don't know...  - Herpes can cause encephalitis.
她没有疱疹
She didn't have herpes.
- 你在说些什么东西  - 别激动
- What are you talking about? - Okay.
她到底怎么了?
What happened to her?
- 她到底怎么了  - 冷静点  冷静点
- What happened to her? - Okay, okay.
艾默霍先生  那边有悲痛辅导人员
Mr. Emhoff, there are grief counselors...
…他们对开导这种失去亲人的悲痛的家属很有帮助
...who are very helpful with this sort of passing, okay?
你可以向他们寻求一些帮助
You might find some resolution there.
现在  我只能说很抱歉
Now, I am sorry.
喂?
Hello?
挂掉电话  赶紧拨911  马上拨打911报警
Hang up the phone and call 911 right now. Right now. 911.
他说他头痛  所以我让他睡一下
He said he had a headache, so I put him to bed.
我觉得他没有呼吸了
I don't think he's breathing.
克拉克  克拉克
Clark. Clark.
噢  天哪  他死了吗
Oh, my God, is he dead?
疾病爆发第5天
瑞士日内瓦
世界卫生组织中心
我们从北京方面得到的消息是
What we are hearing from Beijing is that the outbreak is contained...
在香港爆发的疾病被遏制了
...to the Chrysanthemum complex in Hong Kong.
2人死亡  10例疑似病例
Two deaths and 10 suspected cases.
中国广东省  人口: 九千六百一十万
我们如何定义"遏制"的?
How are we defining "contained?"
他们使用的是特地为非典建立的应急方案
They're using the same protocols established for SARS.
他们在隔离人群并进行症状病人筛选
They're quarantining the complex and screening for symptoms.
九龙是世界上最稠密的人口居住区
Kowloon is the most densely populated area in the world...
…香港的地形是个港湾
...and Hong Kong is a harbor.
疫情会迅速扩散
It's going to spread.
香港正给我们寄来血液样本
Hong Kong is sending us blood samples.
我们也在调查来自伦敦的样本
We're also looking at samples from London.
一个死在旅馆里  另外一个死在健身俱乐部
One at a hotel, the other at a health club.
5人死于脑炎
Five dead, encephalitis.
还有一个死于东京公交车上的男子
And there's the man on the bus in Tokyo.
- 那儿有3人死亡
- 他们中有人去过中国或者伦敦吗?
- Three dead in that cluster.
- Any of them travel to China or London?
我们正在调查
We're checking.
尼尔先生  你要坚持住
Mr. Neal, I want you to stay with me here.
能听到我说话吗  你以前有过癫痫发作吗 尼尔先生?
Can you hear me? Have you had seizures before? Mr. Neal?
- 如果可以请睁开你的眼睛  - 他还有呼吸吧?
- I want you to open your eyes if you can.  - He's breathing, right?
我叫不醒他  我回到家就发现他这样了  我叫不醒他
I couldn't wake him. I got home, I couldn't wake him.
今天早上起来我们俩感觉很虚弱
We both woke up sick this morning.
小心撞到头
Watch your head.
呃…
Hmm...
大脑皱沟已经被损坏了  检查下其他地方
Well, the sulci are obliterated. Let's look at the base.
噢  天哪
Oh, my God.
要取个样本吗?  还是?
You want me to take a sample, or?
我想让你离手术桌远点儿
I want you to move away from the table.
- 我该通知下谁吗  - 打给所有人
- Should I call someone, or?  - Call everyone.
疾病爆发第6天
嗯  这种事情总是时不时发生
Well, these things happen up there from time to time.
游泳之后在学校宿舍里得了脑膜炎…
Meningitis in a college dorm after a swim meet...
…或者在某个湖边的夏令营感染了西尼罗病毒
...or  in some summer camp near a lake.
我听说去年夏天他们那里爆发了一次肠病毒性脑炎
I was reading that last summer they had an
outbreak of enterovirus encephalitis.
103个案例  大部分染病者是小孩
A hundred and three cases, mainly children.
现在这个时节那个地方非常冷
Well, it's probably too cold up there for that right now.
截止昨晚  共有5人死亡  32个疑似案例患者
As of last night, there were five deaths and 32 cases.
小学校园里人群聚集
There's a cluster in an elementary school.
你必须得做好准备应付这类事情
That's the kind of thing you have to be prepared for.
新闻一定会铺天盖地
It's gonna be all over the news.
你觉得当务之急是什么?
What's your single overriding communications objective?
我们正在隔离确认感染了的病人
和那些我们认为可能被传染的人
We're isolating the sick and quarantining
those who we believe were exposed.
好的  不错
Okay, good.
从现在开始  我们电话保持联系
As of this moment, you and I are attached at the cell phone.
如果你需要什么资源  打电话给我
如果你卷入政治争论  也可以打给我
If you need resources, call me.
If you get into a political dogfight, call me.
如果你凌晨3点还睡不着   盯着墙上的时钟
If you find yourself wide awake, staring at the walls at 3 a. M...
…思考为什么要接手这个工作  打电话给我
...wondering why you took the job, call me.
希望你带了比较保暖的衣服
I sure hope you packed something warmer than that.
我们前往调查的地方可是易感风寒之地
We're looking at around zero with the wind chill.
不想看到你感冒
Don't want you to catch cold.
你想先去旅馆吗
Do you wanna go to the hotel first, get situated?
如果可以  我希望立即开始工作
I'd prefer to get started, if that's possible.
- 好吧  - 办公室离这有多远
- Okay. - How far is the office?
大约半个小时路程
About a half-hour from here.
你爸爸被隔离了
Your dad's in isolation.
你可以站在窗口边  用电话和他交谈
ou can go up to the window, pick up
the phone, and you can talk to him.
- 嘿  - 爸爸
- Hey.  - Dad.
- 嘿  - 你病了吗
- Hey. - Are you sick?
没有  没有  没有  我…呃…
No, no, no. I'm... Uh...
这只是预防措施  他们要确认下
This is all just, you know, a precaution.
They're, you know, just making sure.
但你和他们在一起  你可能会感染的
But you were with them. You could still get it.
不  我不会的  嗯  他们说这病发生得太快了
No, I won't. Um, they said this happens really, really fast.
呃  我没事  不用担心我
And, uh, I'm fine. There's nothing wrong with me.
我一切正常  我们没事的  我们没事
There's nothing wrong with me. We're okay. We're okay.
克拉克呢
And Clark?
这个  我  呃…
Yeah, you know, I, um...
我当时不在家  当时我在医院急救室陪着贝丝
I wasn't there. I went, uh, in the ambulance with, uh, Beth.
呃…  我只是… 我
And, uh, I just didn't... I...
我把他留给卡丽・安妮照看
I left him with, uh, Carrie Anne.
我应该呆在那儿的
I should have been there.
- 我本可以帮忙的  - 不  不 这不是你的错  宝贝儿
- I could have helped.  - No, no, no. Honey, no, no.
很庆幸你当时不在家  我很高兴
It's good that you weren't there. I'm happy.
如果你有什么三长两短  我是说…我
If something had happened to you, I mean, I'd...
宝贝儿  你现在一切都好  我很高兴
Honey, you're here now, you know. I'm happy about that.
我很庆幸
I'm happy about that.
你什么时候可以回家?
When are you coming home?
很快  很快   他们…
Soon. Very soon. They, you know...
- 你还是去你妈妈家吧  - 不要
- Why don't you go, uh, to your mom's? - No.
- 留在威斯康星州  - 不要  她不需要我
- Just stay in Wisconsin.  - No. She doesn't need me.
她有丹陪着  我要留下来
She's got Dan. I live here.
你没人陪伴  我不会丢下你的
You don't have anybody. I'm not leaving you.
截止今天下午5点  共有47例疑似病人  8人死亡
We have 47 cases and eight deaths as of 5 this afternoon.
现在是周末  这些数字可能会低点
It's a weekend. These numbers might be low.
人们都呆在家里观察几天  看情况是否好转
People are staying home for a couple days, see if they get better.
根据这点判断  我认为是呼吸感染
At this point, I think we have to believe this is respiratory.
- 也可能是受感染的衣服和被褥等  - 什么意思?
- Maybe fomites too. - What's that, fomites?
呃  是指病毒通过表面介质传播
Uh, it refers to transmission from surfaces.
平均每人每天触摸他们自己的体表2-3000次
The average person touches their face 2- or 3000 times a day.
- 2-3000次每天?
- 醒着的每一分钟平均触摸3-5次
- Two- or 3000 times a day?
- Three to five times every waking minute.
期间  我们会接触门把手…
In between, we're touching doorknobs...
…饮水机  电梯按钮  还有其他东西等
...water fountains, elevator buttons and each other.
这些东西会变成污染物源
Those things become fomites.
这是我们要公布的东西?  呼吸系统疾病和污染物?
Is this something we wanna release to the press? Respiratory and fomites?
- 公众会作何反应?
- 很难说  一部电影里的塑料鲨鱼…
- How's the public gonna react?
- Hard to say. A plastic shark in a movie...
…会让人害怕到远离海洋  但是关于香烟的警告
...will keep people from getting in the ocean,
but a warning on cigarettes...
在大家惊慌失措前我们必须通知政府相关人员
We need to walk the governor through this before we freak everybody out.
我是指  我们现在甚至不能告诉公众
他们应该害怕的东西是什么
I mean, heh, we can't even tell people right
now what they should be afraid of.
以前猪流感爆发时我们试过这样做
结果使得健康的人们非常惧怕
We tried that with swine flu.
All we did was get healthy people scared.
这是今年最大的购物周末
It's the biggest shopping weekend of the year.
我们需要考虑关闭学校
We need to consider closing schools.
谁留在家里陪孩子?  他们都在商店上班
And who stays home with the kids? People that work at stores.
政府工作者  在医院工作的人们
Government workers. People that work at hospitals.
什么时候我们才知道这是什么病毒?
是什么引起的? 什么药物可以治愈?
When will we know what this is?
What causes it, what cures it?
这些可以让公众保持镇定
Things that keep people calm.
我们需要决定的是:
What we need to determine is this:
因为这些已经感染病毒的人…
For every person who gets sick...
…其他正常的人有多少可能会被感染
...how many other people are they likely to infect?
对季节性流感来说  一般为1
So for seasonal flu, that's usually about one.
如果是天花   这个数字大于3
Smallpox, on the other hand,it's over three.
现在  还没有疫苗之前…
Now, before we had a vaccine...
脊髓灰质炎的传播速率在4-6之间
...polio spread at a rate between four and six.
现在  我们称这些数字为…
Now, we call that number...
R0平均数
(即R0 表示某个传染病患者将疾病传染给其他人的平均数)
(如果小于1 传染病就会自己消亡 如果大于1 病毒会传播开来)
the R-nought.
R代表该病毒的繁殖率
R stands for the reproductive rate of the virus.
能知道这种病毒的传输速率吗?
Any ideas what that might be for this?
传播速度取决于多种因素
How fast it multiplies depends on a variety of factors.
病毒的潜伏期  一个人会感染的时期长短
The incubation period, how long a person is contagious.
有时候即使人们没有症状也会有传染性
Sometimes people can be contagious
without even having symptoms.
我们必须清楚这个
We need to know that too.
我们需要知道容易感染该病毒的人群的基数有多大
We need to know how big the population of
people susceptible to the virus might be.
这样说来所有有手、嘴和鼻子的人都有可能了
So far that appears to be everyone with hands, a mouth and a nose.
只要我们知道了R0的平均数值
我们就可以着手处理大规模的疫情
Once we know the R-nought,
we'll be able to get a handle on the scale of the epidemic.
这么说这是种流行病  什么流行病?
So it's an epidemic now. An epidemic of what?
我们已经给疾控中心寄去了样本
We sent samples to the CDC.
如果幸运的话  72小时之内就可以知道是什么病毒了
In 72 hours, we'll know what it is, if we're lucky.
很明显  我们不太走运
Clearly, we're not lucky.
BLS-4级生物安全实验室
(共分四个等级 BSL-1  BSL-2 BSL-3  BSL-4)
明尼苏达州的一个年轻女子最近去中国旅行过
A young woman in Minnesota, recently traveled to China.
她儿子也死了
Son also died.
截止今天早上  87个疑似病例  15人死亡
As of this morning, 87 cases, 15 deaths.
- 感恩节过得如何?  - 我在加班
- Did you have a good Thanksgiving? - I worked.
你加班?  真的吗
You? Really?
得克萨斯州  沙门氏菌  病毒数量很少
Texas. Salmonella. Pretty limited.
- 我感恩节过得不错  谢谢你的询问  - 噢
- Mine was great, thanks. - Oh.
病毒呈现多形性 但主要倾向于卵形
It's pleomorphic, but tends toward ovoid in shape.
表面结构看起来很像糖蛋白
I see structures on the surface
that look like glycoproteins...
但是没有病毒特有的形态
...but there's nothing morphologically pathognomonic.
我们测试了她身上所有的抗体
交叉反应不多
We tested all her antibodies.
I didn't see much cross-reactivity.
她的身体完全没有抵抗能力  情况不断恶化
Her body had no idea what to do with it. It just kept amplifying.
把这个发给旧金山的萨斯曼
Send it to Sussman in San Francisco.
如果他也查不出这是什么病毒的话  没人会知道了
If he doesn't know what it is, nobody does.
这种病毒显示了新奇的特性
跟原生细胞嵌合在一起
It shows novel characteristics
and appears to be chimeric in origin.
病毒有15至19个碱基长度  拥有6-10个基因
Virus is 15 to 19 kilobases in length and
containing six to 10 genes.
典型的副粘病毒
Typical of a paramyxovirus.
是哥斯拉、金刚和弗兰肯斯坦的结合体
It's Godzilla, King Kong and Frankenstein all in one.
- 等一下  我等下给你打过去  - 你已经到了
- Hold on. Shit, I'll call you back.  - You've got it in there.
- 离开这儿  - 病毒从何而来? 是军方泄露的吗?
- Get away from here.  - Where'd it come from? Military?
你既不是医生  也不是作家
You're not a doctor and you're not a writer.
不  我是个作家  没错
Yes, I am a writer. Yes, I am.
写个博客可算不上作家
只不过是标点符号的拼凑罢了
Blogging is not writing.
It's graffiti with punctuation.
我是个记者  我的博客有知情讨论相关的板块
I am a journalist, and there's informed
discussion on the blogosphere...
…这种病毒是生化武器
...that this is a biological weapon.
你想和我谈的话  打个电话去我办公室预约吧
You wanna talk to me, call my office
and make an appointment.
疾病爆发第7天
- 米切尔医生?  - 是我
- Dr. Cheever? - Yes.
- 你有时间吗  - 有
- Do you have a moment? - Sure.
我们找到他了  告诉在去他家路上的人来这里
We found him. Tell the unit on the way to his house to come in.
抱歉  请问你是?
Excuse me. Who are you?
我是Dennis French  是国土安全部门的
My name is Dennis French with the
Department of Homeland Security.
你来的目的是?
And what's this all about?
海军少将汉格迪希望我们能前往紧急行动中心
Rear Admiral Haggerty's expecting us in
the emergency operations center.
到那儿后我们可以讨论下
We can discuss it there.
这是发生在九龙的
This happened in Kowloon.
今天我们发现了一些澳门赌场的
工作人员引起了格外的注意
Today we've got workers at a casino
in Macao striking over conditions.
3人死在工棚里  CIA认为这之间有某种联系
Three have died in one bunkhouse.
CIA thinks there may be a connection.
赌场是国土安全部门特别留意的地方
Casinos are of particular concern to Homeland Security.
一些人在披萨店或者当地市场里准备爆发了
Someone's ready to blow themselves up
at a pizzeria or the local market...
他们认为自己感染了天花
...the thought of getting
themselves sick with smallpox...
进过拥挤的赌场  他们一定这样想过
...and walking through a crowded casino
must have crossed their mind.
这3人的死因是什么?
What did they die of, the three?
报告上说一个未知  一个是癫痫发作 一个昏迷
Reports are vague. Seizures, comas.
我们已经接触了世界卫生组织  看看他们查到些什么
We've reached out to the WHO, see what they know.
如果你有什么计划   现在是行动的最佳时机
If you were gonna plan it, can't think of a better time.
- 计划什么  - 攻击
- Plan what? - An attack.
有人能对抗禽流感吗
Is there any way someone
could weaponize the bird flu?
人不需要对抗禽流感
Someone doesn't have to weaponize the bird flu.
禽兽会这么做
The birds are doing that.
官方报告说要关闭郊区的
Officials are reporting the closing of
Mondale Elementary School...
明尼阿波利斯蒙代尔小学
...in suburban Minneapolis...
以此预防最近爆发的不明疾病
...in response to the recent outbreak
of a still-unknown disease...
该疾病已经让一个学校护士和3个学生送命
...that has so far taken the life of a school nurse and three students.
其他281区域的学校仍然照常上课
Other schools in District 281 will remain open...
但是家长们被通知让任何有症状的孩子留在家里
...but parents have been notified to keep
home any children with symptoms.
健康部门在等待确认信息
The Department of Health is awaiting confirmation...
但有消息表明这些新病例可能和
...but sources say these new cases
may be connected to the sudden death...
34岁的安德森市高级行政管理人
...of a 34-year-old AIMM Alderson executive...
和她的6岁的儿子这个周末双双猝死有关
...and her 6-year-old son this holiday weekend.
大家好  我是米尔丝医生
Hello. I'm Dr. Mears.
我是瘟疫情报中心人员(CDC-EIS)
I'm an Epidemic Intelligence Service officer...
我从亚特兰大赶来是想调查贝丝・艾默霍的死因
...and I'm here from Atlanta to find out what happened to Beth Emhoff.
好了  我会提些问题看是否…
Okay, I'm gonna ask you some questions and see if...
这有个她从香港寄来的包裹
There was a package she messengered from Hong Kong.
- 我用剪刀拆开了  我不确信是否…
- 没事  这没什么关系
- I opened it with scissors. I'm not sure if...
- No. It shouldn't be an issue.
病毒在盒子里活不了几天
Virus can't live for days on a box.
我们一起做过普拉提
We did Pilates together.
她旅行回来后我打给她的
我从没收到过她的信件
I called her after she got back.
I never heard from her.
- 所以你没和她接触过?  - 是的
- So you had no contact with her? - No.
- 她去上过课吗  - 没看到她去过
- Did she go to the class? - I didn't see her there.
她走那天我们一起喝了咖啡
We had coffee the day she left.
她移动了下我的杯子
因为杯子放在了几张报纸上
I think she might have moved my cup
because it was on some papers.
- 我记不起来了  - 几天以前?
- I can't remember. - How many days ago?
大概10天
About 10 days.
没关系  潜伏期低于这个时间段
That's okay. The incubation period is less than that.
还有其他人可能和她接触过吗?
Is there anyone else who might have had contact with her?
- 所有人都和她接触过    - 亚伦・巴恩斯和贝丝接触过
- This was everyone. - Aaron Barnes did.
巴恩斯?  他在另一层楼工作
Barnes? He worked on another floor.
巴恩斯有她需要的文档  他去机场接的她
There were documents she needed.
He picked her up from the airport.
巴恩斯去机场接的她?  巴恩斯现在在哪?
He picked her up from the airport? Where is he?
喂?
Hello?
- 你好  巴恩斯先生吗?  - 你好  我是
- Hello? Mr. Barnes? - Hello? Yes.
我是疾控中心的米尔丝医生
This is Dr. Mears from the Centers for Disease Control.
- 我认为…  - 嗨
- I believe...  - Hi.
嗨  我相信你上个星期和贝丝・艾默霍接触过
Hi. I believe you may have had contact
with Beth Emhoff last week.
是的  我去机场接她  怎么了?
Yeah, I picked her up at the airport.
What's this about?
- 你今天感觉如何?  - 呃  老实说  很难受
- And how are you feeling today?
- Uh, pretty cruddy, to be honest.
我头很痛  可能是被什么小虫子咬了
My head is pounding.
I probably picked up some bug.
- 你现在什么地方?  - 去上班的公交车上
- Where are you right now? - I'm on the bus, heading to work.
- 我建议你立即下车  - 什么?
- I'd like you to get off immediately. - What?
- 他在公交车上  - 哪个位置?
- He's on a bus. - Where?
- 哪儿  公交车在哪个地方  亚伦?  - 嗯… 呃…
-Where? Where's the bus, Aaron?  - Em... Uh...
- 现在刚到Lake and Lyndale. 怎么了?
- 他在Lake and Lyndale.
- Lake and Lyndale. What's going on?
- Lake and Lyndale.
我需要你立即下车
I really need you to get off that bus.
很有可能你已经感染了传染性疾病
It's possible you've come in contact with an infectious disease...
并且有高度的传染性  明白了吗?
...and you're highly contagious. Do you understand?
我要你马上下车  远离人群  避免和人接触
I want you to get off now.
And stay away from other people.
现在我该怎么做?
Now what do I do?
不要触碰任何人  不要与任何人说话
Don't talk to anyone, don't touch anyone.
这是最重要的事情
That's the most important thing.
- 我们会派人去接公交车  - 好的
- We'll send somebody to meet the bus. - Okay.
我现在过去接你  亚伦
I'm on my way to you now, Aaron.
我孩子怎么办?  我接触过他们了
What about my kids? I touched them.
那是一个新工厂的奠基仪式
It was a groundbreaking ceremony for a new factory.
她因为工作需要经常出差
She traveled a lot for work.
她的工作会涉及到以任何方式与牲畜接触吗?
Did her work involve contact with livestock in any way?
- 你家里养了什么宠物吗  - 没有
- Did you keep any pets at home? - No.
没有养
No.
她有提过说和带病的人见过面吗?
Did she mention seeing anyone who was sick?
在飞机上?
Anyone on a plane?
没有
No.
她早上11:15经过芝加哥的海关…
She went through customs in Chicago at 11:15 a. M...
然后乘飞机在下午6点到达明尼阿波利斯
...and then took a flight to Minneapolis at 6 p.m.
知道她在芝加哥临时滞留期间都做过什么吗?
Any idea what she did in Chicago during that layover?
比如开会?
Did she have meetings?
有什么事情让她必须离开机场?
Is there any reason she might have left the airport?
为什么这么问?  难道芝加哥有人感染了这种病吗?
Why? I mean, is there someone sick in Chicago?
呃  在我们结婚之前  我妻子和一个
Uh, before we were married, my wife had a relationship...
叫做乔恩・尼尔的人有过一段感情
...with a man in Chicago named Jon Neal.
乔恩・尼尔感染了?
Is Jon Neal sick?
我们是因为他而传染的?
Did we get this from him?
- 我们在调查所有的可能性
- 不  我觉得我有权利知道事情真相
- We're investigating all the possibilities.
- No. I think I have a right to know.
看看我现在呆的这个地方
Look at where I am here.
- 我不能透露信息  抱歉
- 不是  我只是想弄明白
- I can't disclose that information. I'm sorry.
- No, I'm just... I'm just trying to understand.
我理解
I know.
从萨斯曼那儿得到的结果一样
We're getting the same results as Sussman.
我们已经给病毒测序  确定病毒源
We've sequenced the virus, determined its origin...
我们制作了病毒侵入肺和脑细胞的过程模型
...and we've modeled the way
it enters the cells of the lung and the brain.
这种病毒含有蝙蝠和猪的基因序列
The virus contains both bat and pig sequences.
深绿的部分代表猪  浅绿色代表蝙蝠
The dark green is pig, and the light green is bat.
这里你可以看到交叉事件的发生过程
And here you can see the crossover event.
呃  蝙蝠  蝙蝠  然后是猪  蝙蝠
Uh, bat, bat, and pig, bat.
这个模型阐述了病毒是如何寄宿在宿主身上
And here is a model of the virus and how it attaches to its host.
蓝色的部分是病毒  金色的是人类基因
红色部分是病毒附着蛋白
The blue is virus, and the gold is human,
and the red is the viral attachment protein...
绿色代表人体细胞内的受体部分
...and the green is its receptor in the human cells.
这些受体在呼吸道以及…
These receptors are found in the cells of both the respiratory tract...
…中枢神经系统的细胞内都有发现
...and the central nervous system.
这些病毒就像钥匙插进锁里一般附着在细胞上
And the virus attaches to the cell like a key slipping into a lock.
世界上的某个角落  一头倒霉的猪遇到了带病的蝙蝠
Somewhere in the world, the wrong pig met up with the wrong bat.
- 你见过这种病毒吗
- 没有  而且这种病毒一直在变化着
- You ever seen anything like this before?
- No. And it's still changing.
病毒识别我们人类细胞的速度比人类基因识别病毒快多了
It's figuring us out faster than we're figuring it out.
病毒就只干这个了
It doesn't have anything else to do.
这么说我们遇到的一种新型病毒
So we have a novel virus with a mortality rate in the low 20s...
而目前没有治疗方法  也没有疫苗
...no treatment protocol, and no vaccine at this time.
完全正确
That is correct.
从现在开始  就让BSL-4全力负责研究这个
(BSL 生物安全实验室 BSL4为最高等级)
From here on out, I want no one working on this except at BSL-4.
我们还需要做的是停止其他实验室继续研究这个病毒
Last thing we need is for this to walk out of
the lab on the bottom of someone's shoe.
这里是萨斯曼医生办公室
Dr. Sussman's office.
是我  Ally Hextall
Lan, hi. Ally Hextall.
我们需要关掉你的实验室  这件事情太棘手了  呃…
We need to shut you down. This thing's too hot. Uh...
- 现在只授权给BSL-4级实验室来负责
- 这是个错误的决定
- BSL-4 only at this point.
- I think that's a mistake.
销毁你那儿的样本  呃  销毁一切相关的东西
Cook your samples. Uh, destroy everything.
- 我们不能冒险  - 我们正有所进展
- We can't risk it.  - We're making progress.
把这个交给政府管理的BSL-4级实验室来做太不明智了
You limit this to government-run BSL-4s, it'll take forever.
我可以办到的
I can do this.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
随便你
Yeah.
当然了 艾丽.
Sure, Ally.
你能重复下目前为止受感染的城市吗
Can you repeat the affected cities so far?
再说一次  受到感染的城市有…
Again, the affected cities are...
明尼阿波利斯  芝加哥  洛杉矶  波士顿和盐湖城
Minneapolis, Chicago, Los Angeles, Boston and Salt Lake.
我们期望这个名单增长的速度…
We expect that list to grow...
… 人们都度假结束返家了
...as people return home from their holidays.
什么事?
Yes?
米切尔医生  有多少人已经感染了病毒?
Dr. Cheever, how many people are infected...
…死亡人数是多少?
...and how many have died?
这些数字在我们讲话的同时不断变化着
Those numbers are changing as we speak...
所以我给你的数字很可能要低些
...so any figure I give you is likely to be low.
我们在精确计算这个时间段的死亡率
We're still calculating the mortality rate at this time.
呃  米切尔医生  你是否注意到
Uh, Dr. Cheever, are you concerned...
现在疾控中心面临着一个诚信的问题
..that the CDC faces a credibility issue here...
…自从对H1N1的过度反应后?
...after the perceived overreaction to H1 N1?
我倒是希望事情发展证明我们真的反应过度了
I'd rather the story be that we overreacted...
总比因为我们做的不够导致许多人失去了生命好吧
than that many people lost their lives because we didn't do enough.
这是我们站在这里的原因
That's why we're here.
这也是为什么世界卫生组织要派
一名流行病学家前往香港调查
It's also why the World Health Organization
is sending an epidemiologist to Hong Kong.
不调查病毒的源头很难去深入调查病毒
Hard to know what it is without where it came from.
我们的首要工作就是找到病毒源头
Our first job with these things is to find ground zero.
查出它是如何流入人群开始传播的
Figure out how it jumped into the population.
我们知道一个在明尼苏达州的患者
...We do know that a patient in Minnesota...
曾经去过全球很多地方旅行
traveled to that part of the world.
香港  人口: 七百一十万
我们相信目前大约有89,000个疑似病例
We believe that there are approximately
89,000 cases at this point...
我们将面对的是可能有267,000人会感染
...and that we are heading toward 267,000.
从那儿开始  利用我们建好的模型 基于R0平均数为2…
And from there, using our model, based on an R-nought of two...
这些是未来48小时会扩散到的地区
...here is where we expect to be in 48 hours.
米切尔医生  也许你有什么进一步的消息
Dr. Cheever, perhaps you can update us on the research.
目前为止  没人找到一个成功的
培育病毒在细胞内的成长的方法来
As of right now, no one has found
a good way to grow the virus in cells.
为什么
Why is that?
因为病毒杀死了我们放进去的所有细胞
不管是猪的细胞  或者鸡的  所有生物细胞都一样
Because it kills every cell we put it in.
A pig, a chicken, everything.
除非能培育这种病毒  而且是大量的
不然没法做实验
Until we can grow it, and a great deal of it,
we can't experiment with it.
在这之前  我们不能接种疫苗
And until then, we can't vaccinate against it.
你们找到任何的治疗方法了没?
任何有用的抗体?  有吗?
Have you found any treatment at all?
Any antivirus? Anything?
没有
No.
贝丝・艾默霍在澳门赌场使用过一个自动取款机
Beth Emhoff used an ATM at a casino in Macao.
花旗银行给出了她的账单记录
Citibank released her records.
她在10:43的时候使用过这台ATM
当时刚从赌场出来
We have her using the machine at 10:43
just off the casino floor.
我需要查看赌场这2个小时内的监控录像
I wanna see the casino security footage
for two hours on either side of that.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
哦  他们是我老家的村民
他们那儿发现了新的感染人群
Oh, they're from my village.
They found a new cluster there.
抱歉
Oh.
- 你家里人还在那儿吗
- 我的母亲出现了症状
- Is your family still there?
- My mother has symptoms.
我给你取监控录像  稍等
I'll get you the footage you require. Excuse me.
萨斯曼医生  我听说他们打算中止我们进行实验
Dr. Sussman, I heard that they were shutting us down.
是的  我正要处理这些样本
Yeah, I just have to deal with the samples.
如果只是销毁他们  我能胜任这个工作
If it's just a matter of destroying them, I can do it.
不用了  我来就行  你回家吧
No, I'll take care of it. You go on home.
我做完后会再核对下数据
I'll do that, and then I just
want to recheck some data.
他培育成功了
He grew it.
他通过抗体和免疫膜攻击复合体
He tried antibodies and immunological MAC outlines...
但关键是来自吉朗的蝙蝠胎儿细胞株
...but the key was a fetal-bat cell line from Geelong.
- 我们没有这个东西
- 他在3级的生物安全实验室就培育成功了
- We didn't have it.
- He grew it in a BSL-3.
艾丽  他在BSL-3级实验室都干什么工作?
Ally, what the hell was he doing working with it in a BSL-3?
忽视我
Ignoring me.
他一定会把这个发布的  妈的  他想要什么?
He's gonna publish. Shit. What does he want?
一盒雪茄  他本可以有选择的  埃利斯
A box of cigars. He had a choice, Ellis.
他完全可以自己一人靠着这个发财
He could have gone into business for himself.
毫无意问他已经培育病毒成功了
但是他把这个给了我们
There's no doubt he was approached,
but he gave it to us.
- 这么说我们只能相信他?
- 看来我们只能这样了
- And we're supposed to trust him?
- We don't have a choice.
美国疾病预防控制中心…
The Centers for Disease Control and
Prevention in the United States...
以及瑞士世界卫生组织
...and the World Health Organization in Switzerland...
今天证实  旧金山的萨斯曼医生
...confirmed today that Dr. Lan Sussman of San Francisco...
已经成功地在实验室环境中成功培育出MEV-1病毒
...has succeeded in growing the MEV-1 virus in a laboratory setting.
疾病预防控制中心的官员说现在取得的突破
Officials at the CDC cautioned that the
breakthrough is only the first step...
只是研制疫苗的第一步
...toward developing a vaccine...
离人体试验阶段至少还有几个月
...which is likely still months away from human trials.
世界卫生组织估计
全球受感染人群超过8百万
The WHO estimates the number of people
infected worldwide to be over 8 million.
现在情况有所改变
Now it all changes.
萨斯曼成为国家科学院的受膏者
Sussman gets anointed by the National Academy of Sciences...
所有的医药行政人员都变得苛刻
...and every pharmaceutical executive  gets a hard-on.
他们会在地球上所有的实验室培育这种病毒
They'll be growing the virus in every lab on Earth.
对猕猴来说真是糟糕的一天
It's a bad day to be a rhesus monkey.
我们先是让他们进入大家的视线
现在我们要全神贯注于病毒
Crikey, first we shoot them into space,
now we'll be shooting them full of virus.
所以现在就是需要你专业知识的时候了
So this is where we need your expertise.
医药股票已经达到高盘了
Pharmaceutical stocks are already through the roof.
接下来是什么?  机遇在哪里?
What's next? Where's the opportunity?
是你首先看到日本公交车上死亡男子的视频的
Now, you saw that Shinko bus thing day one.
那才是我们会面的目的
That's why we wanted this meeting.
今天早上当我打开电脑时
When I turned on my computer this morning...
我的博客有超过200万访问人次来寻求真相
...I had over 2 million unique visitors, all looking for the truth.
你认为他们会愿意看到我和对冲基金的人谈判吗
You think they wanna see me talking to some hedge-fund guy?
克鲁姆维德先生  我们不是发明需求的
Mr. Krumwiede, we don't invent need here.
我们只是分析和预测
We just analyze it, predict it.
你直接告诉我  多少的报价你才愿意
You tell me what it costs to look into your crystal ball.
你真像连翘
You're familiar with forsythia?
- 不  我不是  - 我想告诉你的是…
- No, I'm not.  - What I'm about to tell you is backed up...
备份的证据将会短暂的出现在媒体面前
...by testimonials that will appear shortly in the media.
我会找个时机进行广泛的讨论
I'll be talking about it extensively in the days ahead.
连翘是干什么的?
What does forsythia do?
是一种药物
It's the cure.
如果我是免疫的  你不能用我的血液来治疗吗
If I'm immune, can't you use my blood to cure this?
培养血清需要很长一段时间  而且很昂贵
Blood serums can take a long time to make
and are very expensive.
但好的一方面是你不会得病
But the good news here is that
you're not going to get sick.
好的  呃…
Okay. Um...
你的意思是我女儿也不会染上这种病毒了  对吧?
Then that would mean that my daughter can't get it either, right?
我不能保证
I can't promise you that.
但她不是会继承我的一些基因吗
But isn't that something that she would inherit from me?
这个嘛  她一半的免疫系统来自于你
Well, half her immune system came from you...
但另一半免疫系统继承的是她妈妈的
...but the other half came from her mother.
快3个小时了
Almost three hours.
我需要医生或者护士来给我检查下
I need to see a doctor or a supervisor or something.
我想知道他是否也感染上了报道中说的那种病毒
I wanna know if he has this thing on the news.
很抱歉  但是我们已经在尽力了
I'm sorry, sir, we're doing the best we can.
我能和你们的负责人谈谈吗?  不管是谁都行
Can I just speak to an administrator or something? Anybody.
先生 请耐心一点  我们会让你…
Sir, please be patient. We'll get you in...
他病了
He's sick!
在车库的时候 我妻子让我脱掉了衣服
y wife makes me take off my clothes in the garage.
然后她给我准备了一桶温水和肥皂
Then she leaves out a bucket of warm water and some soap.
我离开后她把所有东西都消毒了
And then she douses everything in hand sanitizer after I leave.
我是想说  她有点反应过度  对吗
I mean, she's overreacting, right?
不尽然  还有别摸你的脸了  戴维
Not really. And stop touching your face, Dave.
好了  我们把气障病患者安置在这儿
Okay, we'll put the air lock here.
放25排  每排10张床  发烧最严重的病人安排在那边上
I want 25 rows of 10 beds apiece. The most febrile cases at this end.
联邦应急管理署会负责食物供应这块
We'll set up triage outside, FEMA can
handle food in the basement...
我们必须在接下来的24-48小时内完成
...and we'll need to be operational
within the next 24 to 48 hours.
知道了
Gotcha.
- 做得好 戴维  这个应该有效  - 谢谢
- Nice job, Dave. This will work. - Thanks.
现在还需要3个这样的地方
Now find me three more just like it.
打扰了 米尔丝医生 这些花费是由你负责还是我们自己出?
Excuse me, Dr. Mears. Is this coming out of your budget or ours?
世界卫生组织已经证实了香港的样本
WHO has confirmed that the Hong Kong sample...
和伦敦、东京以及阿布扎比的病毒是匹配的
...matches London, Tokyo and Abu Dhabi...
我们还在检测法兰克福和开罗的感染人群
...and we're seeing large clusters in from Frankfurt and Cairo.
查找病毒源头携带者有什么进展没?
Are we any closer to an index patient?
可能是贝丝・艾默霍或者日本的死在公交车上那人
Could be your Beth Emhoff or the guy on the bus in Japan.
有些人上不了网   你情况怎么样?
Someone else who crawled off the grid. How you doing?
进展不错  我准备去会见…
Yeah, good. I'm going into a meeting with...
不是  我不是问你事情的进展
我是问你的身体还好吗?
No, I didn't ask what you were doing,
I asked how you were doing.
你还好吗
How are you doing?
我  呃…
I'm, uh...
我很好
I'm fine.
很好?
Fine?
你也知道  我干这行15年了
You know, I was in the field for 15 years.
我遇到过很多糟糕的事情  如果你感觉不适  随时打电话给我
I've seen a lot of shit. If you're not doing fine, you can tell me.
你试过不得不告诉一个刚刚失去妻子和继子的男人
You ever have to tell a man who just lost his wife and stepson...
她妻子去世前还在欺骗他吗?
...that his wife was cheating on him before she died?
不  我没有这种经历
No, I haven't.
我相信你尽了最大努力
I'm sure you did the best you could.
- 呃 嗯  - 你好像很累了
- Uh-uh.  - You sound tired.
你一定要记得偶尔休息一会儿
You gotta try to remember to sleep once in a while.
还记得上次自动售货机卖不出东西来是什么时候的事了?
When was the last time you had something that
didn't come out of a vending machine?
是在Taco Bell
(快餐连锁)
Taco Bell.
当地官员说超过3000病例被确认感染了病毒
Local officials are now saying over 3000
cases have been confirmed...
在西部郊区地方
...in the western suburbs...
以及拉姆齐、卡尔顿和圣路易斯县报告的首例感染者
...as well as the first cases reported in Ramsey,
Carlton and Saint Louis counties...
病毒在持续蔓延
...as the virus continues to spread.
- 来了  - 国家卫生署发言人...
- Got it!  - A state Health Department spokesperson...
目前呼吁爱荷华州的医院…
...at this hour is appealing to hospitals
as far away as Iowa for medicine.
不要开门  不要开门
No, don't open that door.
Don't open the door.
- 是 安德鲁 - 呃  抱歉  安德鲁  我不能让你进来
- It's Andrew. - Uh, sorry, Andrew, I can't let you in.
我只是过来表示下  艾默霍先生
安慰I just came to give my condolences, Mr. Emhoff.
我明白  谢谢你的关心  呃  但是我不能让你进来
I understand. Thank you. Uh, but I can't let you in.
那我把这些花放在这儿吧
I'll just leave them, then.
不用 最好你一起带走吧
呃  还是谢谢你
No, actually, you should take them.
Uh, thank you, though.
- 我等下给你打电话  - 拜拜
- I'll call you later.  - Bye.
我们不能冒险让其他人进来
We just, you know, aren't gonna take any chances.
- 你知道这个怎么玩吗?
- 不 我完全不懂这个
- Do you know how to play this?
- No, I have no idea what's going on.
不过看起来很有趣
But it looks fun.
你要试试吗
You wanna try?
好吧
Okay.
我玩玩看
We'll see.
你好  你好
Hello. Hi.
噢  轮到我了
Oh, yeah, my turn, okay.
押这个  好的
This one. Crab. Okay.
- 你赢了  - 噢  啊
- Hey. - Oh! Aah!
噢
Oh...
噢  天哪  我…  那是什么?  哪个是?
Oh, my God. I'll do... What is that? Which one is this?
- 筹码  - 那个是筹码
- Coin. - It's a coin.
噢  要吹口气  好的
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
已经开始传播了  我们只需知道具体方向
It's transmission. So we just need to know which direction.
可是也看不出是哪里来的
But we don't know where it comes from.
我认为病毒早于澳门就出现了
I would like to suggest
that the virus started before Macao...
最先出现的地方可能是香港
...and maybe here in Hong Kong.
你的这些猜测都没有足够的证据
不能随便发表声明
You're considering pronouncements
with serious implications.
通过摄影机是看不见病毒的
A virus is too small to be seen on video camera.
疾病爆发第14天
不是吧
Please, God.
不要
不好  不好  不好
No, no, no.
你好
Hello?
我是821房间的艾琳・米尔斯医生
This is Dr. Erin Mears in Room 821.
我需要你查下过去24小时内进入过这个房间的人员名单
I need you to get me the names of everyone
who serviced this room in the last 24 hours.
此外  你还要联系下
Also, you need to get in touch with the waiter...
昨晚到过这个房间的服务员
...who brought me my room service last night.
我需要所有他们的联系方式
家里的电话  手机号 等等
I need all of their numbers.
Home, cell, everything, yes.
米尔丝? 米尔丝?
Mears? Mears?
米切尔医生
Dr. Cheever...
我好像也感染了
...I think I'm sick.
什么?  怎么回事?  你有哪些症状?
What? What's going on?
What kind of symptoms do you have?
咽不下东西  头很痛
Can't swallow. Severe headache. Ahem.
你体温多少度?
What's your temperature?
- 华氏101.8°F(约38.7°C)  - 呃  听着 你不能…  你只是
- 101.8 - Uh, listen, you can't... You just...
- 你现在别慌  好吗  - 我知道
- You can't panic now, okay? - I know.
- 你一个人吗  - 我肯定感染了其他人
- Are you alone? - I've definitely infected other people.
你还不能确定
You don't know that.
- 我该做些什么?
- 嗯  你先留在房间里不要出去
- So, what should I do?
- Well, I want you to stay in your room.
我会通知健康部门  告知他们你的处境
I'll call the Health Department, tell them you're there.
- 艾琳  你不会有事的
- 是的  我知道  我知道
- Erin, just... You're gonna be okay.
- No, I know. I know.
- 好的  - 你得派其他人来执行任务了
- Okay. - You gotta send somebody else.
我会的  你现在不要太担心了  好吗
Yes, but you don't worry about that right now, okay?
- 嘿  我…  -  你照顾好自己
- Hey, I'm... - You take care of yourself.
很抱歉我没能完成工作
I'm sorry I couldn't finish.
没关系  别想太多  我看看有什么办法能让你回来
That's... Never mind that. Let me see
what I can do about getting you back here.
- 我会尽可能让你健康的回来  - 谢谢
- I'm gonna get you home if I can, healthy.
- Thank you.
- 你要坚持住  - 拜拜
- Now, you hang in there.  - Bye.
再见
Bye. Bye.
现在的问题是  我们不能运送尸体
The problem is, we just can't take delivery of the bodies.
我们自己的员工有些保险方面的问题
We have insurance issues with our own employees...
更别提要考虑送葬者的健康问题
...with our union, not to mention the health of the mourners, to consider.
我只是想把我妻子和继子安葬了
I just...  I wanna bury my wife and my stepson...
找一个我的朋友和家人能来举行仪式的地方
...and have a service where our friends and our family can come...
方便让他们悼念下
...and pay their respects and grieve.
我理解你的心情  请节哀顺变
I understand, and I am truly sorry about your loss.
你考虑过其他的方式吗?
Have you considered other options?
他们怎么能这样做  现在这儿有奇案
How can they do that? We have a family plot here.
他们让我们考虑下火化
They want us to think about cremation.
他们说目前这种情形  火化是最安全的方式
They just say that it's the safest thing in a situation like this.
我想把我女儿和外孙
I wanna be buried with my daughter and grandson...
和我父母葬在一起
...with Jack and my parents.
我想大家能在一起
I want us all together.
他们不会运送的  萨拉
他们不会运送尸体
They're not gonna take them, Sarah.
They're not gonna take the bodies.
我会想想办法
I'll figure something out.
她确实犯过错误  米奇
She made mistakes, Mitch...
但是我知道她很爱你
...but I know she loved you very much.
我去买点喝的来  怎么样?
I'm gonna use some of these to
get us some drinks, okay?
现在无法接通乔恩・尼尔
You have not reached Jon Neal...
你可以选择留个短消息
...but you will if you leave a message.
嗨  是我  呃…
Hi. It's me. Um...
我查过航班了  我可以赶上更早点的飞机
I checked the flights, and I can actually get an earlier flight...
如果可以在芝加哥滞留5个小时的话
...that would give me a five-hour layover in Chicago...
如果你想让我做点什么  请给我电话
...so let me know if that's something that you'd like me to do.
- 这是给你的小费  - 噢  谢谢
- That's for you, okay?  - Oh, thank you.
非常感谢  谢谢
Thank you very much. Thank you.
- 你忘了手机  - 噢  天哪
- Excuse me.  - Oh, my God.
谢谢
Thank...
- 这个乌克兰人捡到了艾默霍的手机
- 这表明有接触
- Emhoff gave it to the Ukrainian.
- That just shows contact.
也可能是其他方式传播的  李辉的情况如何?
Maybe it went the other way. What about Li Fai?
- 他当时也在赌场  -  看看这个
- He was on the casino floor.  - Watch this.
喔  噢  太好了  过来一起合个影吧
Whoa. Oh, good. Okay, come on.
Let's get one together. Ready?
干杯
Cheers.
嗯
Mm.
走吧
Let's go.
这个就是12：08时和艾默霍在一起的那个人
That's him with Emhoff at 12:08.
我可以给你看下电梯的
监控录像拍下的那个乌克兰女人
I can show you the Ukrainian woman
on the security camera in the elevator...
倒退到20分钟之前她的房间的画面
...going back to her room 20 minutes earlier.
在李晖开始工作前她就走了
She was gone before Li Fai started work.
病毒源自这儿
It came from here.
艾默霍是首例病人
Emhoff is the index patient.
我们必须查出她来澳门前都去过哪些地方
We need to know everywhere she went before the casino.
我想再看看她的行程安排
I want to see her itinerary again.
他们说法国和美国人有治疗方法
They say the French and Americans have a cure.
他们在秘密的研制
They're manufacturing it in secret.
世界卫生组织也知道  但他们和美国人是串通的
WHO knows, but they're in bed with the Americans.
- 听谁说的  - 网上传言
- Who says? - The Internet.
- 网上传言?  你相信吗?  - 我不确定
- The Internet? And you believe it? - I don't know.
你妈妈怎么样?
How's your mother?
我们试过给她服用连翘  但是她没能熬过去
We tried forsythia, but she wasn't strong.
大屿山有个万人坑
(香港境内最大的岛屿)
There's a mass grave in Lan Tau.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我准备把这些交给政府部门的人
我们要把这些寄去日内瓦
I'm taking this to the ministry.
We need to send this to Geneva.
你和我一起去
I need you to come with me.
- 你要做什么?  - 求你了
- What are you doing? - Please.
不要
No.
怎么回事?  孙峰  怎么了  你在干什么?
What's going on? Sun Feng.
What's going on? What are you doing?
- 你在干什么?  - 对不起
- What are you doing? - I'm sorry.
我们不能再等了
We couldn't wait any longer.
当他们在治愈其他人的时候   我们…
While they cure each other, we're here...
是最后才能得到救治的人
...at the end of the line.
整个村子就剩这些人了
This is what is left of my village.
- 他们都感染了吗?  - 还没有
- Are they sick? - Not yet.
我们会努力不让他们感染
And we're gonna keep it that way.
在他们找到治愈方法前你必须呆在这儿
You'll stay here with us until they find a cure.
我在这儿能帮什么忙?
How is that gonna help?
你必须想办法让我们优先得到治疗
You're gonna get us to the front of the line.
米尔丝医生
Dr.Mears.
米切尔医生又来电话了
Dr. Cheever called again.
现阶段我们也很艰难  没有足够的能力送你回去
We're just having a hard time
with the logistics of evacuating you.
找架飞机什么的
Finding a plane and all.
你的手机在我这儿
I got your phone.
米切尔医生交代  如果你方便可以给他打个电话
Dr. Cheever, he asked you to call if you feel up to it.
我们为医护人员和急救先遣队
Now, we're setting up a special ward...
在学校里准备了一个特殊的病房
...for medical personnel and first responders at the university.
我想把你转移到那儿去
I wanna move you there...
但护士工会现在请求停工
...but the nurses' union is calling a work stoppage...
直到有效治疗感染的方法出现
...until protocols are in place.
他们都是志愿者  但是…
There are volunteers, but it's just...
现在很难确定什么地方是比较安全的
It's hard right now to know where's the right place.
你在要求我在一个病人身上使用过量的资源
You're asking me to spend a lot of resources on one person...
目前这个情形  我不能那么做
...and right now, I can't do that.
我想米切尔医生也会赞同我的做法
Dr. Mears would agree with me.
她是自己人  是我们派她去出任务的
She's one of our own, Lyle. We sent her up there.
好吧  是我派她去的  我希望能带她回来
Okay, I sent her up there. I would like to go get her back.
我们有架配有隔离舱的飞机
We have a plane with an isolation pod...
特地为我们的人感染后回来用的  对吗?
...to bring our people in the field home when they're sick, right?
到底怎么了  莱尔
What's going on, Lyle?
华盛顿伊利诺伊州的一个众议员病倒了
There's a sick congressman from Illinois in D.C.
他在芝加哥度假
He was in Chicago over the holiday.
他正乘坐这架飞机返回家
They're using the pod to fly him home.
之后他们打算关闭中途岛和芝加哥奥黑尔国际机场
Then they're closing down Midway and O'Hare.
政府人员正调用国民警卫队  目前在设置路障
The governor is calling the National Guard.
They're setting up roadblocks.
他们正关停贸易和公共交通
They're shutting down trade, public transportation.
已经禁止通行了
The Teamsters are pulling drivers off the road.
- 还是会有漏网之鱼的  - 没错
- People are still gonna slip through.  - Yes, they will.
特勤局正转移总统到秘密基地
The Secret Service is moving the president underground.
国会的人正考虑如何通过网络来解决问题
Congress is figuring out how to work online.
如果这些话传出去
When the word goes out...
这些银行、加油站、杂货店肯定会大乱的
...there will be a run on the banks,
gas stations, grocery stores, you name it.
公众将会惊慌失措  到时候可比病毒还棘手了
People will panic. The virus will be the least of our worries.
会闹翻天的
It will tip over now.
我们只是需要尽可能封锁消息
We just need to make sure
that nobody knows until everybody knows.
我体温是华氏101°(约38.3°C)
My temperature's 101.
比之前更高了
Higher than it was earlier.
我头很痛
My head hurts...
嗓子也很难受
...and my throat feels like it's closing.
这个是连翘
This is forsythia.
自从出现症状一来我就一直在服用
I've been taking it since the onset of the symptoms.
如果我能活到明天  你们就知道这东西是管用的
If I'm here tomorrow, you'll know it works.
真实的血清  我是艾伦・克鲁姆维德
Truth Serum Now. I'm Alan Krumwiede.
大概会死多少人?
How many people are gonna die?
这个嘛  在1918年…
Well, in 1918...
1%的人口最后死于西班牙流感
...1 percent of the population died from Spanish flu.
它是一种新型病毒  就像现在这种病毒  没人见过
It was novel, like this, no one had ever seen it before.
- 1%的美国人死了?
- 是1%的全球人口
- One percent of America?
- One percent of the world.
将有7千万的人会因此丧命  也许更多
As many as 70 million people could die,　baby, maybe more.
- 那我们该怎么办?
- 我不知道  我们在寻求解决方案
- So, what do we do?
- I don't know. We try to figure it out.
这也是我派米尔丝医生前往明尼苏达州调查的原因
This is why I sent Mears up there, to Minnesota.
但现在我不能把她带回来
And now I can't get her back.
她也感染了  奥布里  而我什么也不能做
She's sick, Aubrey, and I can't do anything for her...
因为那里没有护士
...because there are no nurses.
- 为什么没有护士?  - 因为他们正在举行罢工
- Why not? - Because they're on strike.
- 他们怎么能这样做?
- 因为对于这种病毒他们也无能为力
- How can they do that?
- Because there's nothing they can do.
健康的人群正和感染了的病人们相离很近
We're putting healthy people next to sick people...
希望这些健康的人群不会染病
...and hoping the healthy people don't get sick.
- 对此我表示遗憾  埃利斯  但这不是你的错
- 是我派她去那出任务的  奥布里
- - I'm sorry, Ellis, but that's not your fault.
I sent her up there, Aubrey.
逝者已矣 生者如斯  别太自责  好吗
If one in four are dying, that means
three out of four are living, right?
空白时间轴
So the odds are in her favor.
我想你立即驱车前往亚特兰大
I want you to get in your car
and drive down here to Atlanta now.
听到了吗   奥布里
You hear me, Aubrey?
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我想你现在驾车离开芝加哥
I want you to get in your car and leave Chicago.
到亚特兰大去  你自己一人开车
I want you to drive here to Atlanta. Drive by yourself.
抓紧时间  赶紧  不要告诉任何人  中途也别停下来
You do it. You do it now. Don't tell anyone and don't stop.
远离其他人群  明白吗  和其他人保持距离
Stay away from other people, understand?
Keep your distance from other people.
你上路后打个电话给我   奥布里
Call me when you're on the road, Aubrey.
罗杰
Roger.
你刚全听到了?
Did you hear?
我也有家人  米切尔医生
I got people too, Dr. Cheever.
我们都有亲人
We all do.
喂
Hello?
嘿  你怎么不一起吃晚餐?
Hey, friend, what's up with blowing off dinner?
- 对不起 莉斯  - 你怎么感觉怪怪的  你还好吗
- I'm sorry, Liz. - Why you so flaky? You feeling okay?
这该死的流感
This flu sh...
实在是很怪异  埃利斯怎么说?
Stuff is really spooky. What does Ellis say?
他说情况…  他说情况很严重
He says it's... He says it's serious.
很严重是什么意思?
What do you mean, serious?
你在哪儿?
Where are you?
- 我准备离开芝加哥  - 什么?
- I'm getting out of town.  - What?
我透露点信息给你吧
I'm gonna tell you something...
你不要说出去
...and you're not gonna repeat it.
疾病爆发第18天
- 你就不能捂着嘴再咳吗?  - 去你妈的
- Cover your mouth, please. - Fuck off, lady.
今天只有50份剂量的了
We will only be able to give out 50 doses today.
- 什么  - 这是我们的配额
- What? - That's our allotment.
简直是胡扯
This is bullshit.
嘿  那谁  谁允许你插队了  太过分了
Hey. There... Excuse me, there's a line here. Excuse me!
天哪
Jesus.
怎么没有消防人员来救火?
Where's the fire department?
难道都没人值班吗
Is anyone even working here?
你去拿麦片
Just get the cereal.
- 乔瑞  别碰任何东西  -  救救我
- Jory, don't touch anything. - Help me.
赶紧丢掉你的手套
Okay, take your gloves off.
把手给我
Here, give me your hands.
快走  快走
Okay, okay, come on.
- 快走  快   - 嗯
- Come on, come on.  - Unh.
嘿  你们给我滚开点  滚开
Hey, get away from there. Get away.
锁上门
Lock the door.
请回到你的车里  先生  请回到车里
Get back in your car, sir. Get back in your car.
-  不  不 我没感染  我是免疫的 - 请退后
- No, no, I'm not... I'm immune.  - Stay back.
我以前得过
I've already had it.
- 我女儿并没有感染  - 她病了?
- And my daughter's not sick. - She's sick?
她没染病  没有  我们只是想去威斯康星州
She's not, no. We're just trying to get to Wisconsin.
道路已经封锁了  政府要求隔离检疫
The border is sealed. The governor has declared a quarantine.
请回到你车里
Get back in your car.
不  我们才不要回去  我们想离开这儿
No, we don't wanna go back there.
We wanna go across.
- 这是不可能的  请回车上去
- 我们没有感染
- There is no way across. Get in your car.
- We're not sick.
请回车上去  否则我要逮捕你了
Get back in your car or I will detain you.
回哪儿去?
Where?
回车上去
Get in the car!
- 怎么了  - 我们必须回去
- What happened?  - We have to go home.
疾病预防控制中心的人在撒谎
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
我觉得自己病发了
I think I had a seizure.
糟透了
Oh.
药店里已经买不到药了
I can't... I can't find any in the stores. I tried.
听着  我这里也没有了  有人闯进来过
Look, I don't have any here. People broke in.
我  我怀孕了  艾伦
I'm... I'm pregnant, Alan.
我有…  我有钱
And I have... I have money.
我可以给你钱
I can give you some money.
洛伦  你不该出来到处走的
Lorraine, you shouldn't be out.
- 求你了  艾伦  - 回家去吧
- Please, Alan.  - Go home.
如果我得到了连翘  到时候我会带给你的
I'll bring it to you when I get it.
我在想能否再弄张毯子来
I was wondering if I could get another blanket.
这张太潮湿了
This one's very damp now.
很抱歉  先生  但是已经没有多余的毯子了
I'm truly sorry, sir. We're out of blankets.
我们希望能收到更多捐赠  我们已经发出公告了
We're hoping for more to be donated. We put the word out.
那暖气呢  温度能调高点吗
What about the heat? Can we turn that up?
我想想办法
I'll find out.
- 装尸袋什么时候用完的?  - 2天以前
- When did we run out of body bags? - Two days ago.
我们想从加拿大再运点来
但是他们想等等看
We're trying to get more in from Canada,
but they just wanna wait and see.
拒绝谎言  拒绝谎言  拒绝谎言
No more lies! No more lies! No more lies!
网上传言说印度和其他地区
There are stories on the Internet that in India and elsewhere...
利巴韦林药物在抵抗这种病毒方面有一定疗效
...the drug ribavirin has been shown
to be effective against this virus.
国土安全局告知疾控中心
除非能确保该种药物有足够的库存
Yet Homeland Security is telling the CDC
not to make any announcements...
否则不能发布任何声明
...until stockpiles of the drug could be secured.
嗯  我们会继续评估几种药物的作用
Well, Dr. Gupta, there continue  to be evaluations of several drugs.
其中包括利巴韦林
Ribavirin is among them.
但目前的情况  抵御病毒最好的方法是远离人群
But right now, our best defense
has been social distancing.
不要握手  如果染病一定要留在家里
No hand-shaking, staying home when you're sick...
经常洗手
...washing your hands frequently.
你能告诉我们  迄今为止
有多少人死于这种病毒吗
Can you tell us, to date, how many people have died from this virus?
很难说  我们正在努力确认这个统计数字
Very difficult. We're still working
on, uh, confirming that number.
全国有50个不同的州
There are 50 different states in this country...
意味着有50个不同的健康部门
...which means there are 50 different Health Departments...
拥有50种不同的应急方案
...followed by 50 different protocols.
现在有请艾伦・克鲁姆维德参与到讨论中来
Let me bring Alan Krumwiede into this debate as well.
呃   艾伦是个自由撰稿人
Uh, Alan's a freelance journalist.
呃  他是第一个跟踪调查"日本新光公交车死亡男子"视频的人
Uh, he was the first to track the "Shinko Bus Man" video.
呃  艾伦  今天在推特上
Uh, Alan, today on Twitter...
你说关于这种病毒的真相一直被
...you wrote that the truth about this virus
is being kept from the world...
疾控中心  世界卫生组织掩盖着
...by the CDC, by the World Health Organization...
让某些人从中窃取暴利
...to allow friends of the administration to benefit from it...
包括财政上和物质方面
...both financially and physically.
嗯  目前我们知道有些药物在防治病毒方面
是有一定疗效的  比如连翘
Uh, there are therapies we know
are effective right now, like forsythia...
但这些并没有公布在疾控中心的官网上
...and they don't even appear  on the CDC website.
在你的博客中  还写到
On your blog, you also wrote...
世界卫生组织和制药公司是串通好了的
...that the World Health Organization
is in bed with pharmaceutical companies?
因为他们确实是串通的
Because they are.
他们就是从中获利的代表  他们狼狈为奸
That's who stands to gain from this.
They're working hand in glove.
他们的贼手正伸向我们的口袋
And the hand is reaching into our pockets.
疾控中心在研究连翘和其他同类疗法
The CDC is exploring forsythia and other homeopathic treatments.
但是目前  没有科学依据能支撑这些言论
But right now, there's no science to back any of these claims.
米切尔医生或者掌控他的幕后人士能因此获利
Or no way Dr. Cheever or the people who put him into power can profit from it.
我们不排除任何可能性
We're not ruling anything out.
人们被感染了  他们快要死了  而我们却在这…
There are people who are sick, people who are dying
and we are doing...
他们不再保证我们的安全
They're not keeping us safe
from this any more than...
我们关心所有的美国公民的生命安全
We're concerned about every American citizen.
米切尔医生在说"每个美国公民"的时候是有点虚伪的
Dr. Cheever is being a bit disingenuous
when he says "every American citizen."
我们在竭尽全力寻找病毒源头  如何抵御病毒
We're working very hard to find out
where this virus came from, treat it...
以及接种疫苗
...and vaccinate against it if we can.
问题是我们目前还没有发现  我们还没找到有效的方法
We don't know all of that yet, we just don't.
我们目前所知的是病毒传染的方式有
What we do know is that in order to become sick...
和带病毒的人群有接触
或者摸过这些病人碰过的东西
...you have to first come in contact with
a sick person or something they touched.
大家要保持镇定  不要被谣言蛊惑
In order to get scared, all you have to do
is come in contact with a rumor...
或者网上传言等
...television or the Internet.
我觉得克鲁姆维德先生散步谣言的危害
比这种疾病本身还要危险得多
I think what Mr. Krumwiede is spreading
is far more dangerous than the disease.
-  噢  真的吗  - 没错
- Oh, really?  - Yes.
- 真是搞笑  - 有什么好笑的
- That's funny. - What's funny?
你在说笑吧  如果大家有上Facebook的话
You're funny, because if you check on Facebook...
你们会发现这都归咎于米切尔医生
...you'll find a communiqué attributed
to Dr. Cheever by Elizabeth Nygaard...
在公布芝加哥人群检疫结果前做过不光彩的事情
...about the quarantine of Chicago hours
before it was announced to the public.
这就是我认为他有点虚伪的原因
That's why I think he's a bit disingenuous...
当他说会平等对待所有人
而不仅仅是他的朋友们时
...when he says equal care
for all and not just his friends.
米切尔医生 你打算如何回应这些指控
Some pretty wild allegations here, Dr. Cheever.
你能透露下这个交谈的内容及发生时间吗
Can you tell us what communication appeared and when?
你和Nygaard之间真正的关系是什么?
What is the nature of your relationship with Nygaard?
我没有在任何社交网站上看到这件事情归咎于我的新闻
I'm not aware of anything attributed to me on any social network.
我确定你没有  事实摆在那儿  事实摆在那儿
I'm sure you're not. It is there. It is there.
告诉他们R0平均数为2真正的含义  米切尔医生
Tell them what an R-nought of two really means, Dr. Cheever.
给他们讲点数学知识 如何?
Teach them some math. Hm?
你不愿意?  我可会这么做
No? I'll do it.
第一天  有2个人感染  然后会有4个人感染
On day 1, there were two people with it
and then there were four.
接下来是256人    再然后是65000人
...but next it's 256, and then it's 65,000...
你会发现你周围的人很多都感染了
...and it's behind you, above you, and all around you.
如此持续计算30步  将会有10亿人感染
In 30 steps, it's a billion sick.
只需要3个月时间   这个大家都可以很容易计算出来的
Three months. It's a math problem you can do on a napkin.
这就是我们会面临的事实
And that's where we're headed.
这就是你不愿意告诉我们死亡人数的原因
And that's why you won't even tell us the number of the dead...
你会告诉我们吗  米切尔医生?
...will you, Dr. Cheever?
但你却告诉你的朋友们赶在其他人之前
But you'll tell your friends when to get out of Chicago...
离开芝加哥
...before anyone else has a chance.
他们只是在寻找替罪羊
They're looking for a scapegoat.
你别想太多
You just made it easy.
我们没和总检察长说的原因是
The only reason we're not taking this to the attorney general...
现在找不到人来顶替你
...is because we can't replace you right now.
但是会对你进行调查  你明白了吗
But there's gonna be an investigation. Do you understand that?
此外  我们不想再看到你上电视
And we don't wanna see you in front of the cameras anymore.
疾病爆发第21天
喔  喔   喔  这是哪来的
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where did you come from?
- 被替换了  - 结果是好是坏?
- It's mutated.  - Which way, better or worse?
赶上非洲艾滋病感染人口了
It's moved into an African HIV AIDS population.
德班的人群太分散了
The Durban cluster is highly divergent.
现在有了新的R0平均数  埃利斯  不再是2了
We have a new R-nought, Ellis. It's not two anymore.
我还以为你说一旦我们培育成功病毒
就可以研制疫苗预防它了
I thought you said once we could
grow it, we could vaccinate against it.
我们试图利用死亡的病毒
和蛋白质神经组织结合来增强免疫反应
We tried using dead virus combined
with atrophins to boost immune response.
结果呢
And?
没有产生保护性的抗体  死了很多用于试验的猴子
No protective antibodies, a lot of dead monkeys.
- 好的一方面呢
- 现在我们必须试试减毒株病毒
- Can you get to the good news?
- Now we have to try a live attenuated virus.
- 像小儿麻痹症那种  - 没错
- Like with polio? - Exactly.
减毒株唯一危险的是
The only danger with a live virus...
它可能会恢复到野生型并杀死宿主
...is the possibility that it will revert to wild type and kill the host.
什么时候能得到试验结果
And when will we know about that?
这得问那些试验猴子了
I'll ask the monkeys.
截止目前  感染人群死亡率在
As of right now, the mortality rate is fluctuating...
25%-30之间波动
...between 25 and 30 percent...
根据基本的医疗条件
...depending upon underlying medical conditions...
社会经济因素、营养供给、新鲜的水
...socioeconomic factors, nutrition, fresh water.
随着新的突变
With the new mutation...
我们预测RO平均数不会小于4
...we are predicting an R-nought of no less than four.
加上没有疫苗  我们预料…
And without a vaccine, we can anticipate...
这个星球上多达1/12的人口将会感染这种疾病
...that approximately one in 12 people
on the planet will contract the disease.
疾病爆发第26天
大家请注意
Folks, attention.
感谢大家的耐心  我们也在尽力而为
We appreciate your patience
and we're doing the best we can.
我们已经用完了本来为今天准备的肉食
We have exhausted our supply
of meals ready-to-eat for today.
什么
What?
请大家保持镇定  我们会…
Please remain calm. We'll be sending...
请…   嘿   有人能去帮帮忙吗
Please... Hey. Can we get some help over here?
请大家保持秩序
Leave the park in an orderly fashion.
救救我
Help me!
- 你还好吗  - 谢谢
- You okay? - Thank you.
-  对不起  他们抢走一个  - 到卡车那边看看
- Sorry, they got one of them.  - Get the trucks!
去检查下卡车
Get the trucks!
那儿   那儿什么也没有
There's... There's nothing in there!
有证据表明  现在美国的死亡人数…
As the death toll in the United States is now believed...
已经达到了二百五十万人
...to have reached 2.5 million...
今天总统在一个秘密地点发布了一个声明
...the president issued a statement today
from an undisclosed location...
在达拉斯  克里夫兰 迈阿密和凤凰城发生了暴乱后
...implementing mandatory curfews
in major metropolitan areas...
决定在大城市强制性执行宵禁
...after a second consecutive day of riots
in Dallas, Miami, Cleveland and Phoenix.
执法人员缺勤率接近25%
Absenteeism in law enforcement is nearing 25 percent...
根据报告
...according to reports...
由于大量的911电话打进来…
Because of the high volume of 911 calls...
请遵照以下提示
...please use the following directory:
如果你有该疾病症状  请挂掉电话  拨打专线612-188-6336
If you have symptoms, please hang up and call 612-188-6336.
报告死亡信息或者撤销登记  请按1
To report a death or for the removal of a body, please press 1.
疾病爆发第29天
喂?  有人在家吗?
Hello? Anybody home?
马克在吗
Hey, Mark?
嘿  乔瑞?
Hey, Jor?
乔瑞
Jor?
我的手都冻僵了
I can't feel my hands.
你把我雪天使播放器弄坏了
That messed up my snow angel.
我没感染  乔瑞
I'm fine, Jory.
如果我们两个都没染病  那么我们不会互相传染的
If neither of us have it, then we can't give it to each other.
-  离她远点儿  -  爸爸
- Get away from her.  - Dad!
- 离开这儿 离开这儿  - 爸爸
- Get away. Get away.  - Dad!
- 你干什么?  - 你给我呆那儿
- What are you doing? - Stay there.
回家去吧   安德鲁
Go home, Andrew.
起来
Get up.
有进展吗
Are we even close?
就算我们现在已经培育出有用的疫苗
If we even had a viable vaccine right now...
还得做临床试验  这至少得花几个星期
...we would still have to do human trials
and that would take weeks.
之后必须得到批准
And then we would have to
get clearance and approval...
联系药品制造商和分销渠道
...figure out manufacturing and distribution.
可能要花几个月时间
That would take months.
然后才能对幸存者预防接种疫苗
And then training survivors to give inoculations.
多拖几个月  死亡人数将会更多
More months, more deaths.
国土安全局想知道
Well, Homeland Security wants to know...
我们能否把疫苗投放在输水管道里
就像氟化物那样
...if we can put a vaccination
in the water supply, like fluoride.
可以立即治愈所有人
Cure everyone all at once.
我马上要回家了  埃利斯  现在很晚了
I'm going home now, Ellis. It's getting late.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 你在干什么  - 没事的  爸爸
- What are you doing? - It's okay, Dad.
- 不  这太危险了
- 你还记得巴尼・马歇尔医生吗
- No, it's not okay.
- Do you remember Dr. Barry Marshall?
他认为溃疡是由细菌引发的  而不是压力
Thought that bacteria caused ulcers, not stress.
他给自己注射了药物  最后治好了
Gave himself the bug and then cured himself.
你跟我提起过他
You taught me about him.
我在测试自己研制的疫苗
I'm testing my vaccine.
不  这次情况不同
No, this is different.
我不想看到你染病
I don't want to get you sick.
艾丽  你不能冒险
Ally, you can't take that chance.
噢  爸爸  你能取得现在的成就
是因为你一直注重实践
Oh, Dad, you're here because you
stayed in your practice...
别人都回家了  而你还在治疗病人
...treating sick people after everyone else went home.
你在冒险  你每天都在冒险
You took that chance.
You took that chance every day.
怎么了
What?
他获得了诺贝尔奖
He won a Nobel Prize.
-  是的  我知道  爸爸  呵呵  - 巴尼・马歇尔
- Yes, I know, Dad. Ha, ha.  - Barry Marshall.
食品和药物管理局正在
The Food and Drug Administration
is accelerating approval...
加紧审批MEV-1型号疫苗
...of the MEV-1 vaccine...
当前正在美国和欧洲的5个秘密地点进行生产
...currently in production at five
secret locations in the U.S. And Europe...
据说首批用于人类的疫苗会在未来90天内生产出来
...saying the first doses could be available for human use within 90 days.
世界卫生组织估计这将花费将近1年的时间
The WHO estimates that it could take nearly a year...
来制造和分发出去基本需求数量的的疫苗
...to manufacture and distribute the
necessary amount of the vaccine...
以此抑制病毒的持续传播
...to stop the spread of the virus...
目前该病毒在全球范围内已经夺去了超过260万人的生命
...which so far has taken over 26 million lives worldwide.
在实验室加紧生产救命药物的同时
But as labs work around the clock to
produce the life-saving formula...
哪些人应该首先得到救治?
Who gets it first?
疾病爆发第131天
- 别碰我  - 东西在哪儿?
- Don't touch me. - Where is it?
- 我们没有
- 胡说  他在这儿工作  他肯定是最先得到的
- We don't have it.
- Bullshit. He works there. He gets it first.
我们确实没有  我们必须等到
We don't have it. We have to wait...
- 奥布里? - 埃利斯?
- Aubrey? - Ellis?
你在哪儿
Where are you?
被抢劫是因为他们看到你上了电视新闻节目
而且知道了发生的事情
It's because they saw you on the news
and they heard about what happened.
- 你还好吗  - 他们知道你的住处
- You all right?  - They knew where you worked.
他们等到你离家后才行动
They waited for you to leave.
- 起来坐这儿  让我看看你
- 我曾试过阻止他们
- Get up here. Come on. Let me look at you.
- I tried to stop them.
我试过
I tried.
- 他们碰你了没?  他们看起来像是染病了的吗?
- 他们戴了面具和手套  埃利斯
- Did they touch you? Did they look sick?
They had masks on, Ellis, and gloves.
别告诉我你…  我们明天才能领到疫苗
Don't tell me that...
Aubrey, we get the vaccine tomorrow.
你要相信我  埃利斯
You have to trust me, Ellis.
他们真的没有碰我
They didn't touch me.
在1918年西班牙流感爆发以后  有些人变得富有
After the Spanish flu in 1918, you know, people got rich.
生产维克斯达姆膏和来苏水(一种消毒剂)的人  靠它发财了
The Vicks VapoRub people, the Lysol people, look it up.
一个人死了  另一人靠卖棺材挣钱
One man dies, another man makes money off his coffin.
一个国家捕杀了所有的鸡
然后猪牛羊肉等成为了高需求的东西
One country culls all their chickens,
red meat goes into higher demand.
我又不是第一个靠这种事情赚钱的人
I'm not the first person to make money...
再说我们的免疫系统也在不断变化
..off the fact that our immune system is a work in progress.
医药行业每个季度都会做一次
The pharmaceutical industry do it every quarter.
我可不认为有人愿意错过机遇  艾伦
I don't think anyone is immune to opportunity, Alan.
没有任何研究表明说能证明连翘对这个病毒有疗效
It's just that studies show
that there is no proof that forsythia works.
谁在进行研究工作?
Who conducted the studies?
"有效的定义"是什么?  抵御哪种类型的病毒?
What defines "works"? Against what strain of the virus?
你还记得上次我们会面时谈论的那些研究吗
Did you know about the studies
when we met the last time?
我们可能卷入很大的麻烦
We can get in a lot of trouble...
你真的以为这个疾控中心的Hextall医生
是穿白大褂的耶稣吗?
Do you really think this Dr. Hextall
CDC person is Jesus in a lab coat?
是政府赶着要试验
The government rushed the trials.
律师们让这些制药公司免于受罚
The lawyers indemnified the drug companies.
这些药物可能会在10年后引起自闭症或嗜睡症
Maybe it causes autism or narcolepsy
or cancer 10 years from now.
谁知道呢?
Who knows?
你… 这个…
You... The...
猪流感疫苗于1976年爆发后遗症  让许多人送命
The swine flu vaccine killed people back in 1976.
神经性疾病
Nerve disease.
所以我们现在全都是小豚鼠
So we're all guinea pigs, starting from today.
等等  他们就如制作电影的人
在一开始就会声明有哪些副作用
Just wait, they'll start listing side effects
like the credits at the end of a movie.
人们信任你  艾伦  如果你告诉他们不要服药
People trust you, Alan. If you tell them not to take it...
没错
That's right.
他们信任我  这1千2百万访问者们
They trust me. All 12 million unique visitors.
我是一个值得信任在媒体前发表言论的人
I'm a trusted man stepping up to a microphone...
在大量的民众面前
...in front of a very large crowd.
我就是这种人  这就是名人效应
That's who I am. That's the brand.
我说的一切全是合理的
I say the right thing, nobody shows up for their shot.
也许他们宁愿相信连翘是有作用的
Maybe they'd rather roll the dice with forsythia.
我可以办到
I can make that happen.
我只是想知道我在合适的位置来做这些事情
I just wanna know I'm in the best position possible when I do.
什么意思  说真的
What does that mean, exactly?
假如我站在十字路口  我想知道…
If I'm gonna step into the crosshairs,
I wanna know what's in...
- 他是和你一起的吗  - 什么  你说谁?
- Is he with you?  - What? Who?
你是不是带了窃听设备?
Are you wearing a wire?
艾伦  我没得选择  他们看到了你博客
Alan, I didn't have a choice. they've seen your blog.
抓住他
Get him.
- 看你跑得了多远  -  为什么抓我  告诉我
- Far enough, far enough.
- For what? Tell me, for what?
涉嫌证券欺诈  合谋  过失杀人
Securities fraud, conspiracy, and most likely manslaughter.
- 它把我治好了  连翘治愈了我
- 我们会查明白的  艾伦
- It cured me. Forsythia cured me.
- We'll see, Alan.
这明显是诱捕行为
This is entrapment.
你不能抽我的血液
你不能这么做,那是我的私人财产
You can't take my blood.
You can't, that's my property.
我们也许永远也不知道病毒的起源地
We may never know where this disease came from.
但是我们知道这个疫苗
But we do know that this vaccine is the result...
是很多人用毅力和勇气换来的
...of the courage and perseverance of a remarkable few.
现在我们开始摇号  约翰
We shall now begin the drawing. John.
首批接受MEV-1疫苗接种的是…
The first MEV-1 vaccination...
…出生日期为3月10日的人群
...are those people born on March 10th.
3月10日
March 10th.
必须提醒大家在排队的时候  相互之间要
We remind all of you to stay 10 feet apart from each other...
保持10步的距离
...while on line.
你不是该在下面的吗
Shouldn't you be downstairs?
我在跟踪疫苗批号
I'm tracking vaccine batch numbers.
这个是你眼下必须做的工作吗
This is what you have to be doing right this minute?
这是我眼下很想做的事情
This is what I want to do right this minute.
放松下  艾丽
Take a bow, Ally.
大家已经失去了很多
People have for a lot less.
你给自己打针算不上什么难事
It's not that hard to give yourself an injection.
米尔丝医生  我爸爸他们怎么样了? 还有你
What about Mears or my father or you?
等你在国会面前被带走的时候我能放松下?
I'm gonna take a bow
while you get hauled in front of Congress?
他们问起来我该怎么说
What do I say when they ask about that?
你告诉他们我跟一个自己心爱的人说了
她又告诉另外一个心爱的人
You tell them that I told a loved one
who told a loved one...
而且我下次还会这么做
...and that I'd do it again.
艾丽   你拯救了上百万的生命
Ally, you have saved millions of lives.
这是一个伟大的故事  也可能变为现实
That's a great story. It also happens to be true.
现在  你多久能说一次?
Now, how often can you say that?
下一批接受MEV-1疫苗接种的市民是…
The next citizens to receive the MEV-1 vaccination...
…是出生日期为…
...are those born on the date...
是哪天?  1月11日
What is that? January 11th.
好吧  已经叫到第114批了
Okay. All right, 144.
那个…  那还有  呃  200…
That's... Ahem. There's still, uh, 200...
还有超过200个出生日期没叫到呢
所以还是有希望的
More than 200 birthdays, hon,
that haven't been called, so that's good.
是个好数字
That's a good number.
- 如果他们的疫苗用完了呢? - 不会的
- What if they run out?
- They're not gonna run out.
他们一定会满足我们的需求  他们已经承诺过
They have enough to keep up with demand.
They said that already.
也许我和你一样是免疫的  我不需要接种疫苗
Maybe I'm immune like you and I don't even need it.
我们不能冒这种险
That's not a chance we're gonna take.
相反的是我们失去了春天和夏天
So instead we lose spring, we lose summer...
失去了再也不会发生的144天
...we lose another 144 days that don't happen again.
为什么他们不发明一个阻止时间流逝的东西?
Why can't they invent a shot
that keeps time from passing?
一切都会恢复正常的  乔瑞
It's gonna start getting normal again, Jory.
这个怎么称呼  "fish" 用中文怎么说
How do you call this, "fish," in Chinese?
这是鱼
This is yú.
- 太漂亮了  - 谢谢
- This is beautiful. - Thank you.
时间到了  我们必须走了  他们的飞机到了
It's time. We have to run. He just landed.
你继续画画…
I want you to keep drawing...
Assand会来继续上这堂课的  好吗
...and Assand will come and finish the class, all right?
再见
I'll see you soon.
- 再见  - 再见
- See you.  - See you.
3号高速公路旁的荃湾坟场(位于香港九龙)
Tsuen Wan Cemetery off the Number 3 Expressway.
离这里不远  只需要15分钟路程
It's close to where you are now. In 15 minutes.
100份的剂量  不能有政府部门的人或警察
One hundred doses. Nobody from the ministry, no police.
如果我们看到有其他车辆  你就再也见不到她了
If we see anybody else, any other vehicles,
you'll never see her again.
喂
Yes?
是的  我没事  按照他们的要求做
Yes, I'm fine. Please give them what they ask.
我只是想回家
I just wanna go home.
只要我们得到了疫苗
就会告诉你到哪儿去找她
Once we have the vaccine,
we'll tell you where to find her.
- 是法国还是美国的?
- 从法国弄的不够
- Is it French or American?
- We could not get enough from the French.
疫苗是在这里生产的  都是同样的配方
It's been made here. The same formula, though.
我保证是有效的
It is effective, I promise.
全在这儿  小心点
There, be careful.
等等  她在哪儿?
Wait, where is she?
- 我们不确定这是不是真的
- 但我们没有其他选择
- We don't know what it is.
- Well, we have no choice.
Orantes医生在哪?
Where is Dr. Orantes?
等等   我们说好的可不是这样
Now, wait, this is not what we agreed on.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
没事  我很好
Yes, I'm fine.
我没事
I'm good.
噢  我差点忘了
Oh, I almost forgot.
- 这是什么  - 给你的疫苗
- What's that? - Your vaccine.
刚给你注射的是安慰剂
The one you took was a placebo.
什么
What?
世上太多绑架了   不只是这里才会发生
There have been many abductions, not just here.
俄国 墨西哥  到处都有
In Russia, Mexico, all over.
政府官员 科学家  或者西方的大富豪们
Government officials, scientists,
or Westerners with great wealth.
很多犯有组织犯罪或革命性组织
Mostly perpetrated by organized
crime or revolutionary groups...
试图借药品敲诈
...trying to extort medicines.
中国人不和绑匪谈判  这不是我们能决定的
The Chinese don't negotiate
with kidnappers. It wasn't up to us.
我们的供给本来就像其他人一样非常有限
We've got a limited supply, just like everyone else.
莉奥诺拉
Leo... Leonora.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
血液检测结果出来了,克鲁・姆维德先生
Blood results came back, Mr. Krumwiede.
你身体里根本没有病毒  根本没有抗体  你撒谎了
You never had the virus.
You have no antibodies. You lied.
你们的实验室当然会这么说了
Of course that's what your labs say.
连翘有疗效也是谎言
Forsythia is a lie.
这是个谎言  因为你浪费了4百50万美元
It's a lie, and you made $4.5 million for telling it.
你会把这个放到博客上去吗
You wanna blog about that?
你得消失一段时间了  克鲁・姆维德先生  还有你的发财梦
You are going to go away, Mr. Krumwiede,
and so is all your money.
我甚至不敢想象所有的民事诉讼人士将和你对簿公堂
I can't even imagine all the civil suits
people are gonna file against you...
我的想象力一直不错
...and I have a pretty good imagination.
现在你要告诉人们不要接种疫苗
Now you wanna tell people not to get vaccinated...
但接种疫苗是他们能得到的最好的机会
...when that's the best chance  they've got.
真想把你送进监狱
If I could throw your computer in jail, I would.
他被保释了
Made bail.
我们谈完了吗
Are we done here?
很显然  还有像你一样疯狂的一千二百万民众
Evidently, there are 12 million other people as crazy as you are.
你成功保释了  恭喜你
You made bail. Congratulations.
米切尔医生和你妻子的  替我恭喜下奥布里
Cheever and wife. Congratulate Aubrey for me.
我本该和你握手  但是我不想作个坏的榜样
I'd shake your hand, but I don't wanna set a bad example.
呃  等大家可以聚集在一起的时候会有个公务接待的
Um, we're gonna have an official reception
when we can get everybody in one place...
真的很希望你能和我们在一起
...and we really hope you can be with us.
当然  你准备好注射了吗?  我的已经注射了
Sure. So are you ready for yours? I've got mine.
不了  我想她回希望我们能一起做这个
No, I think she's gonna wanna do these together.
- 她准备了一些香槟庆祝  - 嗯
- I know she sprang for some champagne. - Hm.
他们已经安排好了听证会
到时候我们会出庭作证的
They have scheduled the hearings.
We'll both be expected to testify.
谢谢
Right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
头向后仰  安东尼
Head back, Anthony.
可以了
There you go.
很好
Good job.
我不能给他手链  但至少你知道他是安全的
I can't give him the bracelet,
but at least you know he'll be safe.
好的  耐心等待7个月
Yeah, beats waiting another seven months.
好了  你想说点什么?
Okay, what do you say?
- 谢谢你 - 不用谢  Anthony
- Thank you. - You're welcome, Anthony.
你知道握手的来历吗?
You know where this comes from, shaking hands?
不知道
No.
古时候 人们用和陌生人握手的方式
来表明他身上没携带武器
It was a way of showing a stranger you
weren't carrying a weapon in the old days.
- 好了  去做你的功课吧  - 好的
- Good job. Now go finish your homework. - Okay.
好了
Yeah.
通过展示你空的双手来表明你没有危险
You offered your empty right hand
to show that you meant no harm.
- 噢  我以前不知道
- 我希望病毒会知道
- Oh, I didn't know that.
- I wonder if the virus does.
嗯  米切尔医生  非常感谢
Well, Dr. Cheever, thanks.
保重  罗杰
Take care, Roger.
你也一样
You too.
你不会因为这个惹上麻烦吧?
You're not gonna get in trouble for this, are you?
你能安静下吗
Will you be quiet?
我的号码是287  埃利斯
My number is 287, Ellis.
如果我们没有结婚  现在必须得等将近1年
If we weren't married,
I'd have to wait almost a year.
看来我们已经结婚了是件好事
Then it's a good thing we're married.
头往后仰
Hold your head back.
我只是不想他们再找你的麻烦
I don't wanna give them another reason to go after you.
你能安静会儿  把头往后仰点吗?
Will you please be quiet and hold your head back?
嗯  好了
Okay, go.
- 太好了  - 嗯
- Good.  - Mm.
还有这边
And go.
很好
Good.
好了
All right.
就如你所说…
Like you said, baby...
照顾好所有身边的人
...just taking care of everybody that's in my lifeboat.
疾病爆发第135天
爸爸  你要来吗
Dad, are you coming?
好的
Yep.
我只是在找摄像机
I'm just looking for the camera.
翻译: xiaochenjia   校对: 我要挂科了
后期: xiaochenjia@VeryCD
疾病爆发第1天